http://www.jesuit.org.uk/privacy-policy

Skip to main content
Privacy policy
Share on Facebook Tweet Widget
Google+The Jesuits in Britain promise to respect any personal data you share with us and keep it safe.  We aim to be clear when we collect your data and not do anything you wouldn’t reasonably expect.  For more information please read our privacy policy.What this policy coversThe purpose of this privacy policy is to give you a clear explanation about how the Jesuits in Britain and all of its apostolic works use the personal information you provide to us and that we collect, whether online, via phone, email, in forms, letters or in any other correspondence or from third parties.We ensure that we use your information in accordance with all applicable laws concerning the protection of personal information. This policy explains:What information the Jesuits in Britain may collect about you and how we collect itHow we will use that informationWhether we disclose your details to anyone elseYour choices regarding the information you provide to us.If you have any queries about this please contact dataprotection@jesuit.org.uk Who we areThe work of the Jesuits in Britain is governed by the Society of Jesus Trust (registered charity in England and Wales no 230165 and in Scotland no 40490).  This policy of the Society of Jesus Trust covers all the work of the Jesuits in Britain including the following apostolic works:Name of Ministry or apostolic workData administratorEmail addressJesuit Refugee Service, WappingMegan KnowlesMegan.knowles@jrs.netJesuit Missions, WimbledonJoelene Wilkiejoelene@jesuitmissions.org.ukSt Beuno’s Jesuit Retreat Centre, St Asaph Denbighshire Sue RumbleManager@beunos.comMount Street Jesuit Centre, MayfairAnne PaolinoAdmin@mountstreet.infoIgnatian Spirituality Centre, GlasgowJohn HampseyJohn.Hampsey@iscglasgow.co.ukLauriston Jesuit Centre, EdinburghAndrew CassidyPastoral.lauriston@gmail.comCampion Hall, OxfordAlec Thorpbursar@campion.ox.ac.ukHurtado Jesuit Centre, WappingStephen Power SJspowersj@jesuit.org.ukThe Way spirituality journalElizabeth LockThe.way@campion.ox.ac.ukThinking Faith online journalFrances MurphyFrancesmurphy@thinkingfaith.orgThe Heythrop JournalPat Madigan SJp.madigan@heythrop.ac.ukPray as you goEmma HollandEholland@jesuit.org.ukJesuits and Friends magazineFran Murphyfrancesmurphy@thinkingfaith.orgSt Wilfrid’s parish, PrestonChris Lloydstwilfridspa@gmail.comDonhead School, WimbledonMonica Danbursar@donhead.org.ukSt John’s Beaumont School, Old WindsorPaolo Brightpbright@sjb.emailIt includes activities carried out by and on behalf of individual Jesuits and Jesuit novices.Jesuits help to manage the following works, which are separate trusts and have their own data controllers (their respective diocesan trusts)Name of Ministry or apostolic workData administratorEmail addressUniversity of Oxford Catholic chaplaincyRebecca Shortbecky.short@campion.ox.ac.ukManchester Universities’ Catholic chaplaincyBrendan Callaghan SJbcallaghansj@jesuit.org.ukImmaculate Conception Farm St, MayfairPatricia MorganFarmstreetfin@rcdow.org.ukSt Anselm’s, SouthallGerard Mitchell SJgmitchellsj@jesuit.org.ukSt Ignatius, Stamford HillDavid Smolira SJdsmolirasj@jesuit.org.ukPolish Catholic MissionAdam Tomaszewski SJatomasze@gmail.comCorpus Christi, BoscombeSandra Cookccoffice@portsmouthdiocese.org.ukSt Peter’s, StonyhurstTim Curtis SJtcurtissj@jesuit.org.ukSt Francis Xavier, LiverpoolDebbie Reynoldsd.reynolds@sfxchurchliverpool.comSacred Heart, EdinburghAndrew CassidyPastoral.lauriston@gmail.comSt Aloysius, GlasgowAlison Fletcheroffice.manager.staloysius@gmail.com How we collect dataWe collect information in the following ways:1. When you give it to us DIRECTLYYou may give us your information for the following reasons:to receive email updates, newsletters or campaignsto subscribe to or purchase one of our publicationsto complete a registration form for a retreat, course or eventto complete a parish census formto register for sacramental programmesto make a donationto complete a Gift Aid declarationto volunteer in one of our centres or ministriesto receive services from us2. When you give it to us INDIRECTLYYour information may be shared with us by independent event organisers, for example the London Marathon or fundraising sites like Just Giving or Virgin Money Giving.  These independent third parties will only do so when you have indicated that you wish to support the Jesuits in Britain or one of our apostolic works and that you are happy for your details to be passed on to us.  You should check their Privacy Policy when you provide your information to understand fully how they will process your data.We collect information about the online services you use and how you use them, like when you open or click a link in one of our emails, watch a video on YouTube, visit our websites or view and interact with our social media. What data we collectThe type and quantity of information we collect and how we use it depends on why you are providing it.1. SubscribersIf you subscribe to a newsletter we will collect:Your nameYour contact details2. SupportersIf you support us, for example make a donation, volunteer, sign up for an event or retreat, or buy something we will usually collect:Your nameYour contact detailsYour bank or credit card detailsWe retain records of your donations and the events you have attended. If you use your credit or debit card to donate to us, buy something or pay for a registration online or over the phone, we will ensure that this is done securely and in accordance with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard. You can find out more information about PCI DSS on their website - https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/security_standards/index.phpWe do not store your credit or debit card details at all, following the completion of your transaction. All card details and validation codes are securely destroyed once the payment or donation has been processed. Only staff authorised and trained to process payments will be able to see your card details.Where it is appropriate in order to offer you a good service, for example on a residential retreat, we may also ask for:Your religious affiliationYour ageYour occupationYour marital statusInformation relating to your health, disability, and dietary preferencesInformation on your reasons for attending a retreat or courseInformation on your previous experience of retreats or courses.3. ParishionersWe routinely ask parishioners for some or all of the following information:Your nameYour contact detailsYour ageYour photographYour ethnic backgroundFamily members’ names and agesLength of time in the parishIn parishes we also retain records ofYour (and your family’s) involvement in our sacramental programmesYour voluntary service in support of our ministryYour donations to the parish and other charities supported via the parishSensitive dataData Protection law recognises that certain categories of personal information are more sensitive. This is known as sensitive personal data and covers health information, race, and religious beliefs. We do not usually collect ‘sensitive personal data’ about our supporters unless there is a clear reason for doing so, such as ensuring your needs are met if you stay in our residential centre, or to ensure we match you with an appropriate spiritual director. In a parish context sensitive data is helpful for us to support families for example in preparing for sacraments and in understanding the demographic changes in our parish. Why we collect dataWe will mainly use your data to:Provide you with the services, products or information you asked forAdminister your donation or support your fundraising, including processing gift aidLet you know about new services, products and ways you can support usKeep a record of your relationship with usEnsure we know how you prefer to be contactedUnderstand how we can improve our services, products or information.If you enter your details onto one of our online forms, and you don’t ‘send’ or ‘submit’ the form, we may contact you to see if we can help with any problems you may be experiencing with the form or our websites.We may also use your personal information to detect and reduce fraud. How we share dataWe will not normally share your data, neither with other organisations nor among the various apostolic works of the Jesuits in Britain/Society of Jesus Trust (listed in Who We Are above)We will only share your information if:We are legally required to do so, e.g. by a law enforcement agency legitimately exercising a power or if compelled by an order of the CourtWe believe it is necessary to protect or defend our rights, property or the personal safety of our people or visitors to our premises or websitesWe are working with a carefully-selected partner that is carrying out work on our behalf. These partners may include mailing houses and IT specialists. The kind of work we may ask them to do includes processing, packaging, mailing and delivering purchases or magazines, sending postal mail, emails and text messages, carrying out research or analysis and processing payments. We only choose partners we can trust. We will only pass personal data to them if they have signed a contract that requires them to:abide by the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulationtreat your information as carefully as we wouldonly use the information for the purposes it was supplied (and not for their own purposes or the purposes of any other organisation)allow us to carry out checks to ensure they are doing all these things.We will only ever share your data in other circumstances if we have your explicit and informed consent.We will never share, sell or swap your details with any third parties for the purposes of their own marketing or the monetising of your data.For information on cookies please visit our cookies policy. How we store dataWe store information on computers located in the UK. We may transfer data to our reputable third party suppliers as explained above.  They may be situated inside or outside the European Economic Area. We may also store information in paper files.We place a great importance on the security of all personally identifiable information associated with our supporters and users. We have security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal data under our control. For example, only authorised personnel are allowed to access user information and we use secure server software (SSL) to encrypt financial and personal information you input before it is sent to us.While we cannot ensure or guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of data will not occur while it is under our control, we use our best efforts to try to prevent this.Unfortunately, the transmission of data across the internet is not completely secure and whilst we do our best to try to protect the security of your information we cannot ensure or guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of data will not occur whilst data is being transferred.Where you or we have provided a password enabling you to access parts of our websites it is your responsibility to keep this password confidential. Please don't share your password with anyone.We will keep your information only for as long as we need it to provide you with the services or information you have required, to administer your relationship with us, to inform the preferences of our supporters, to comply with the law, or to ensure we do not communicate with people that have asked us not to.When we no longer need information we will always dispose of it securely, using specialist companies if necessary to do this work for us. Your rightsThe General Data Protection regulation gives you certain rights over your data and how we use it. These include:the right in certain circumstances to have inaccurate personal data rectified, blocked, erased or destroyedthe right to prevent your data being used for direct marketingthe right of access to a copy of the information we hold about you (known as a subject access request).If you wish to exercise any of these rights please contact the responsible person in the parish, centre or ministry.  For contact details see above WHO WE ARE.  If you are not sure who to contact please get in touch at dataprotection@jesuit.org.uk so we can direct your enquiry.Subject access requests must be made in writing by post to the responsible person in the parish, centre or ministry with a description of the information you want to see and proof of your identity For contact details see above WHO WE ARE.  If you are not sure who to contact please send your request by post to Data protection, Jesuits in Britain, 114 Mount St, London W1K 3AH.We do not accept subject access requests by email so we can ensure that we only provide personal data to the right person.We will respond within one month of receipt of your written request and confirmed ID. Please provide as much information as possible about the nature of your contact with us to help us locate your records. Please note it is our policy to charge the statutory maximum fee of £10 for a subject access request.Where you have provided your consent for our use of your personal information, you always have a right to withdraw your consent at any time.For more information about your rights under the Data Protection Act go to the website of the Information Commissioner’s Office at ico.org.uk.If you are looking for our cookie policy please visit Cookie PolicyTags: Privacy Policy, Data, GDPR
Show alert
×
Click here for support during the coronavirus pandemic ›
